hi just a quick followup on the
photocopier tear down because I forgot
one thing H this paper uh feed mechanism
you know the thing with the big springs
that sits on top and you lift up and you
can put the photos well that's a
complete mechanism in its own right and
I just lifted it off uh complete with
springs and everything and I forgot to
tear it down so here it is we've
basically got another motor controller
board in here with a huge step motor so
there's some interesting stuff in here
as well it's got uh the paper uh sort of
you know feed tray here which changes it
you know you can adjust the distance of
the uh paper to be uh fed in and it's
got a controller board another stepper
motor it's got some sensors on the back
of that we'll take a look at so um just
a little extra now this paper feed tray
is interesting here as you as you change
this uh slider to adjust the paper width
like this it basically pushes these two
plastic arms here here we go pushes
these two plastic arms on a very nice
little rolling Cog system like that a
little linear Cog system not sure what
you call it and it basically uh puts
this little uh plastic tab here in
between a sensor As you move along
there's actually two sensors in there
you can see them there and as As you
move it along it will
engage like that one sensor there
actually corresponds to one paper Point
here so no sensor at all corresponds to
that paper point then the next paper
Point corresponds to the first sensor
there uh being triggered and then as you
move it
along as you move it in like that then
you'll get two uh sensors triggered and
then as you move to the last position
position there you'll get uh just that
last sensor and it's rather interesting
that they actually these sensors are
pretty much standardized all throughout
the photocopier and inside here they've
uh and on here they've got these uh
these paper flaps to indicate you know
whether or not there's paper there and
when you push down on that they had this
uh s once again the same uh optic
sensors as well plugged into here and
here and the wires going out there and
they could detect once again that lever
so as you press down on that lever there
as the paper presses down on that lever
it either uh engages the sensor or it
doesn't and I must have pulled out like
a dozen of these uh little Optical
sensors throughout the entire
photocopier and they pretty much just
standardized on them and it'll basically
contain an LED and a photo transistor
and you can see the little slit in there
and the Slit in the receiving uh side
over there and if we have a look at this
board here you can see the diode symbol
on there and of course anode and cathode
so they just got a diode on that side
and on this side the emitter and
collector of the photo transistor there
and it's actually a Rome 574 now 574
might be familiar to you because that's
the wavelength of a green LED but I
don't think it uses a green LED I think
that's the model number let's Google it
and sure enough you Google Rome 574 and
you get the complete sensor system it's
a Rome photo interruptor and there it is
it's complete in the case with the uh uh
mounting pins on it and it's got a small
slit 0.5 mm for high Precision um it's
designed for optic control equipment
Fast Response well of course it's going
to be and it's got a built-in visible
light filter as well uh forward current
has uh their absolute maximum ratings
let's go down here and have a look at
the characteristics uh the forward
voltage typically 1. uh3 volts at uh 50
milliamps Drive current for the uh LED
and as for the output characteristics
here we're talking uh 800 nanometers
typical sensitivity it doesn't give you
a Min or Max but as it has like a
daylight uh like a light a visible Li uh
filter on it it's not going to go too
much uh lower than that so that puts it
up into the infrared category so the um
LED would be matching infrared as well
and we've got another motor Drive uh PCB
down in here and you can see the uh
similar uh Power package before s SLA 70
44m another couple of power devices
there you can tell by those Center pins
which are really trying to get the heat
out from the Dy in there and uh you
could probably uh reuse uh that board in
some way shape or form but of course we
have a beautiful big beefy steeper motor
here which uh goes into a a belt system
in there through another sensor there's
another one of those Optical sensors you
can see it clipped into there they're
they're standardized all the way
throughout the photocopier another
clutch there I think there's another
clutch down the bottom here as well
they're all over the place and if I try
and get this mechanism apart it might
require a bit of percussive Maintenance
maybe but uh it should just sort of slip
off
somehow off all these clutches maybe
I've got another screw in there and of
course there's always a screw you
forget that's hidden away in there and
uh these things are just
absolutely
amazingly designed there's so much that
goes into them we got another couple of
clutches down in here does that pull off
anyway we've got another clutch here we
just take off this plastic bit there and
it slides straight off so there was
another at least three clutches in there
beautiful they're a uh they're an agura
again clutch Co a MC 5 NE 41 24 vol DC
3.7 wat clutch beautiful and uh it's
quite a few in there and all the cogs
and stuff like that if you're into those
sort of things and now I can probably
get the stepper motor out too here comes
the stepper
motor ah yeah now we're talking here we
go look at this puppy what do we got
here it looks like we've got an astro
sin I think it is stepper 2 km k36
p5v and that looks really really beefy I
like looks like uh you can really do
some cool stuff with that and of course
when you're ripping these out don't
throw out the cables as well cuz they
often use uh weird ass connectors that
uh you'll need so definitely Salvage the
cable out of these things once you undo
the screws to this thing you can see the
big roller inside there with the big
rubber pads on there to really grip the
paper nice and solid and on this side of
the mechanism here we're in for a bonus
three solenoids fantastic and there we
have it three solenoids these
photocopies are a gold mine you've just
got to imagine how many engineering
hours went into just designing all this
solenoid and paper handling mechanism
and the cogs and the gears and
everything else it's just absolutely
incredible the clutch system
ah this is just the top paper handling
mechanism incredible
[Music]